AUSTIN TAM

Tustin, CA 92782 | Cell Phone: (714) 688 - 6398 | Email: austintaivi@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github | Website

SUMMARY

Recent graduate with a deep interest in data analytics and visualization and equipped with problem solving and ideation skills. Experienced in a variety of tools used in the data analytics world and skilled in data wrangling, analysis and reporting.

SKILLS

- Proficient Data Wrangling, Visualization, and Analysis in R and Python
- ♦ Regression Analysis in Stata
- ♦ Data Querying, and Analysis in SQL
- Storytelling and Visualization creation in Tableau
- ♦ Data Analysis and Reporting in Excel
- ♦ Code Management in Github/Git

DATA EXPERIENCES

UCSB Economics Department | Econ 145 TA

June 2022 - August 2022

Worked with a team, helped to create autograders for over twenty different homeworks. The team mainly coded in R and used Github, as well as R Studio, to share work and data files.

Data Hackathon | Participant

March 2021 - November 2021

- Participated in a quarter long hackathon, where students learned intermediate skills in R, such as web scraping, pdf scraping, various methods using packages such as ggplot2, tidyverse, and kblExtra.
- ♦ Worked with a team to visualize the enormity of the threat that wildfires pose in California. Using data derived from using pdf scraping methods, the team created a multitude of visualizations, including a GIF of all the wildfires in the past thirty years in California.

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Worldhealer Nonprofit | Academic Committee Member

June 2021 - August 2021

- ♦ Collaborated in small groups to create a multitude of academic resources for K-12 students on a variety of global topics to help students to create and be in a more inclusive and understanding community.
- Generated \$100 by independently organizing a sticker fundraiser and managing an Etsy store.

UCSB Athletic Performance Center | Student Manager

August 2019 - June 2022

- Managed all aspects of staffing for 17 team members and compiled new schedules every 3 months.
- Facilitated smooth functioning of gym by managing email communication between the Head Coach, staff members, and sport club team leaders biweekly.

UCSB Athletic Performance Center | APC Specialist

October 2018 - June 2022

- Designed and modified workout programs to help athletes maximize their potential, build strength to optimize physical capabilities during on and off seasons, and ensure safety both in and outside of the weightroom.
- ♦ Worked with athletes 1-on-1 in order to teach and correct form for lifts to maximize safety and efficacy.

EDUCATION

University of California, Santa Barbara

September 2018 - June 2022

B.A. in Economics and Philosophy

GPA: 3.85 | High Honors | L&S Honors (2019 - 2022)

CareerFoundry - Data Analytics Bootcamp

November 2022 - May 2023